nata.org 2019-06-06

# Privacy Policy | NATA

The National Athletic Trainers' Association ("NATA") is the sponsor and provider of [www.NATA.org](http://www.nata.org/). NATA.org provides information and resources designed to enhance the quality of health care for athletes and those engaged in physical activity, and to advance the profession of athletic training through education and research in the prevention, evaluation, management and rehabilitation of injuries.

## Privacy statement

NATA takes your privacy seriously. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want to help you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This privacy policy discloses the types of information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it.

  1. **What personally identifiable information does NATA collect?**

NATA’s primary goal in collecting personal information is to advance NATA’s mission and to maximize your online experience when using our site. NATA collects personally identifiable information when you provide it to us by logging in to the site as a member. Once you log in to the site, you are no longer anonymous to us.

  2. **What anonymous information does NATA collect?**

Your Internet browser has a feature called “cookies” which stores small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to our site. However, cookies tell us nothing about who you are unless you specifically give us personally identifiable information. You do not need to have cookies turned on to visit [www.NATA.org](http://www.nata.org/). In addition, you may elect not to allow cookies to be collected by selecting certain options on your browser. NATA also automatically receives and records information from our servers and from your browser, including your IP address, the time, and information about the page you requested. We may use tracking technologies in a variety of ways, including: 

    * keeping count of return visits to our site
    * accumulating and reporting anonymous, aggregate (data collected in mass), statistical information on site usage
    * determining which features users like best
    * saving your password so you don’t have to re-enter it each time you visit our site.  
 
  3. **How does NATA use the information?**

NATA may use your information to process transactions and to alert you to new information, products and services, events and other opportunities. We may from time to time make your contact information available to other reputable organizations whose products or services we think you might find of interest. Additionally, we may use tracking information to determine how much interest a page generates overall based on aggregate user demographics and traffic patterns to those pages. This helps us continue to better understand our users and their needs.

  4. **Is my use of the site secure?**

We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving your information. Additionally, we implement commercially reasonable security measures at our physical facilities to protect against loss or misuse of your information.

  5. **What are my options?**

Users who would rather not provide the user data requested by our membership application process or provide the required log in information do not need to join or log in to the site. You can still view some of the content and use some of the services offered by our site without being a member of NATA. We also give users the choice to opt not to provide certain personal information when joining.

  6. **How will I know if the privacy policy is changed?**

Any modifications to our privacy policy will be reflected first in this notice of our privacy policy. If there is a material change in our privacy practices, we will indicate on our site that our privacy practices have changed and provide a link to the revised privacy policy. If we intend to use information collected from users in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will send affected users written notice of the change.

  7. **How can I update my personally identifiable information?**

You can correct or change the information collected when you joined by logging on to the site with your ID and password and following the online directions. Users who are experiencing problems or who have questions about how our services work can contact us by eContact Form. Currently, we do not offer users a means by which to completely delete personal information established at the time of joining.

  8. **Privacy of children**

NATA.org is not directed to children under the age of 13. We operate our site in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and do not permit application by, and will not knowingly collect or use personally identifiable information from anyone under 13 years of age.

## Cookie Policy

This is the Cookie Policy for The National Athletic Trainers' Association ("NATA"), accessible from <https://www.nata.org/>

**What Are Cookies**

As is common practice with almost all professional websites this site uses cookies, which are tiny files that are downloaded to your computer, to improve your experience. This page describes what information they gather, how we use it and why we sometimes need to store these cookies. We will also share how you can prevent these cookies from being stored however this may downgrade or 'break' certain elements of the sites functionality.

For more general information on cookies see the Wikipedia article on HTTP Cookies.

**How We Use Cookies**

We use cookies for a variety of reasons detailed below. Unfortunately in most cases there are no industry standard options for disabling cookies without completely disabling the functionality and features they add to this site. It is recommended that you leave on all cookies if you are not sure whether you need them or not in case they are used to provide a service that you use.

**Disabling Cookies**

You can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting the settings on your browser (see your browser Help for how to do this). Be aware that disabling cookies will affect the functionality of this and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies will usually result in also disabling certain functionality and features of the this site. Therefore it is recommended that you do not disable cookies.

**The Cookies We Set**

  * Account related cookies

If you create an account with us then we will use cookies for the management of the signup process and general administration. These cookies will usually be deleted when you log out however in some cases they may remain afterwards to remember your site preferences when logged out.

  * Login related cookies

We use cookies when you are logged in so that we can remember this fact. This prevents you from having to log in every single time you visit a new page. These cookies are typically removed or cleared when you log out to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when logged in.

  * Email newsletters related cookies

This site offers newsletter or email subscription services and cookies may be used to remember if you are already registered and whether to show certain notifications which might only be valid to subscribed/unsubscribed users.

  * Orders processing related cookies

This site offers e-commerce or payment facilities and some cookies are essential to ensure that your order is remembered between pages so that we can process it properly.

  * Surveys related cookies

From time to time we offer user surveys and questionnaires to provide you with interesting insights, helpful tools, or to understand our user base more accurately. These surveys may use cookies to remember who has already taken part in a survey or to provide you with accurate results after you change pages.

  * Forms related cookies

When you submit data to through a form such as those found on contact pages or comment forms cookies may be set to remember your user details for future correspondence.

  * Site preferences cookies

In order to provide you with a great experience on this site we provide the functionality to set your preferences for how this site runs when you use it. In order to remember your preferences we need to set cookies so that this information can be called whenever you interact with a page is affected by your preferences.

**Third Party Cookies**

In some special cases we also use cookies provided by trusted third parties. The following section details which third party cookies you might encounter through this site.

  * This site uses Google Analytics which is one of the most widespread and trusted analytics solution on the web for helping us to understand how you use the site and ways that we can improve your experience. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site and the pages that you visit so we can continue to produce engaging content.

For more information on Google Analytics cookies, see the official Google Analytics page.

  * Third party analytics are used to track and measure usage of this site so that we can continue to produce engaging content. These cookies may track things such as how long you spend on the site or pages you visit which helps us to understand how we can improve the site for you.

  * From time to time we test new features and make subtle changes to the way that the site is delivered. When we are still testing new features these cookies may be used to ensure that you receive a consistent experience whilst on the site whilst ensuring we understand which optimisations our users appreciate the most.

  * As we sell products it's important for us to understand statistics about how many of the visitors to our site actually make a purchase and as such this is the kind of data that these cookies will track. This is important to you as it means that we can accurately make business predictions that allow us to monitor our advertising and product costs to ensure the best possible price.

  * The Google AdSense service we use to serve advertising uses a DoubleClick cookie to serve more relevant ads across the web and limit the number of times that a given ad is shown to you.

For more information on Google AdSense see the official Google AdSense privacy FAQ.

  * We use adverts to offset the costs of running this site and provide funding for further development. The behavioural advertising cookies used by this site are designed to ensure that we provide you with the most relevant adverts where possible by anonymously tracking your interests and presenting similar things that may be of interest.

  * Several partners advertise on our behalf and affiliate tracking cookies simply allow us to see if our customers have come to the site through one of our partner sites so that we can credit them appropriately and where applicable allow our affiliate partners to provide any bonus that they may provide you for making a purchase.

  * We also use social media buttons and/or plugins on this site that allow you to connect with your social network in various ways. For these to work the following social media sites including;

will set cookies through our site which may be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies.

**More Information**

Hopefully that has clarified things for you and as was previously mentioned if there is something that you aren't sure whether you need or not it's usually safer to leave cookies enabled in case it does interact with one of the features you use on our site.

### Questions, comments

However if you are still looking for more information then you can contact us through one of our preferred contact methods:

  * By visiting this link: <https://www.nata.org/contact>
  * **Office Phone:**  214.637.6282
  * **Member Services:**  972.532.8897 / 800.879.6282

Questions regarding this privacy statement, cookie policy, or regarding any other aspects of NATA.org or its subdomains, should be sent to the IT department via [contact](https://www.nata.org/contact) form. We try to reply promptly to every message. We may also file your comments to improve the site and program, or review and discard the information.

This policy has been last updated May 24, 2018.
